Mia Farrow Collection 2010.0060
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
Mia Farrow Collection
2002-2011
2010.0060
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
3.5 Linear feet
Farrow, Mia, 1945-.
Abstract
The collection contains correspondence, newspaper clippings, notes, photographs, writings, and speeches pertaining to Ms. Farrow's activism and advocacy in Africa, particularly regarding Darfur, Sudan and neighboring countries.
Biography
Mia Farrow is an internationally acclaimed actress and humanitarian activist. Farrow was born Mia de Lourdes Villiers Farrow on February 9, 1945, in Los Angeles, California, to Australian film director John Farrow, and Irish actress Maureen O'Sullivan. Farrow has appeared in over 40 feature films and television shows, as well as numerous documentaries. One of seven children, Farrow survived polio at age nine, and was appointed a UNICEF Goodwill Ambassador in September 2000. Farrow has worked tirelessly to raise funds and awareness for children whose lives have been affected by violence in countries such as Angola, Chad, the Central African Republic, the Democratic Republic of the Congo, Haiti and Nigeria. Farrow has lectured extensively at colleges and universities around the United States and Canada on the genocide in Darfur and the plight of refugees in neighboring countries, and also contributes regular op-ed pieces to the Wall Street Journal and other newspapers, as well as maintaining her own blog at http://miafarrow.org.
Scope and Content
The Mia Farrow Collection contains correspondence, newspaper clippings, notes, photographs, writings, and speeches pertaining to Ms. Farrow's activism and advocacy in Africa, particularly regarding Darfur, Sudan. There are also materials relating to Chad, the Central African Republic, and the Democratic Republic of the Congo. The collection does not contain information on Ms. Farrow's career as an actor or her personal life.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged chronologically in three series.
Series I: Travel and Advocacy Documents ( 2002-2010 ).
Series II: Speeches and Writings ( 2006-2011 ).
Series III: Audiovisual Materials ( 2006-2011 ).
Separated Material
The following materials have been separated from the collection and cataloged:
The Darfur Archives Dodd DVD 135
Darfur Archives Raw Footage. (20 disks) Dodd DVD 147-166
Restrictions on Access
Researchers must sign a statement of confidentiality to not identify the names or email addresses contained in this collection. Materials containing personal email addresses have been redacted. Records in electronic form are not available for research.
Acquisition Information
The Mia Farrow Collection was donated by Ms. Farrow in 2010. Additions to the collection were received in 2011 and 2012.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to human rights issues. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the Reading Room desk.
Farrow, Mia, 1945-; Correspondence.; Notes.; Photographs.; Speeches.
- Series I: Travel and Advocacy Documents, 2002-2010
  - UNICEF Publications, Sudan, 2003 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Maps of Sudan and Darfur, 2004 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Notes from trip to Sudan, 2004 November (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - Printed Materials from trip to Sudan, 2004 November (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - Travel Documents from trip to Sudan, 2004 November (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - Travel itineraries from trip to Sudan, 2004 November (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - Articles and Clippings, 2004-2006 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - Maps of Darfur and Sudan, undated (Oversize OS)
  - Maps of Darfur and Sudan, 2005-2006 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - Reports of children in Darfur, 2005-2006 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - Photographs, 2006 (Box 1:, Folder 10)
  - Articles about Mia Farrow, 2006-2010 (Box 1:, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence with Kofi Anan, 2006 (Box 1:, Folder 12)
  - Refugee camp profiles, 2006 (Box 1:, Folder 13)
  - Reports, 2006 (Box 1:, Folder 14)
  - Travel to Darfur with Ronan Farrow, 2006 June (Box 1:, Folder 15)
  - Itineraries for Travel to Darfur with Ronan Farrow, 2006 June (Box 1:, Folder 16)
  - Background Articles for Travel to Darfur with Ronan Farrow, 2006 June (Box 1:, Folder 17)
  - Darfur Peace Agreement, 2006 (Box 1:, Folder 18)
  - Darfur Documents, 2006 (Box 1:, Folder 19)
  - Central African Republic, 2007 (Box 1:, Folder 20)
  - Report: Genocide in Slow Motion, 2007 (Box 1:, Folder 21)
  - Report: Sudan and Oil, 2007 (Box 1:, Folder 22)
  - Interivews with Mia Farrow, 2007-2010 (Box 1:, Folder 23)
  - Interviews with John Prendergast, 2008 (Box 1:, Folder 24)
  - Articles about travel to the Democratic Republic of the Congo, 2008 (Box 1:, Folder 25)
  - Background articles for travel to the Democratic Republic of the Congo, 2008 (Box 1:, Folder 26)
  - Maps, Democratic Republic of the Congo, 2008 (Box 1:, Folder 27)
  - Reports: Democratic Republic of the Congo, 2008 (Box 1:, Folder 28)
  - Travel to the Democratic Republic of the Congo, 2008 (Box 1:, Folder 29)
  - Invitations, 2008 (Box 1:, Folder 30)
  - Olympics, 2008 (Box 1:, Folder 31)
  - Children's drawings from refugee camps in Chad, 2009 (Box 1:, Folder 32)
  - Voices from the Refugee Camps, undated (Box 1:, Folder 33)
  - Children's drawings from Djabal refugee camp, 2007; 70 items (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Child's Math Notebook - Goz Amir refugee camp, 2007; 1 bound notebook containing blood splatters, 1 handwritten context note by Mia (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Exhibit Darfur, 2008; 1 postcard (Box 5, Folder 54)
- Series II: Speeches and Writings, 2006-2011
  - Speeches and writings by others, 2002-2010 (Box 1:, Folder 34)
  - Blog Entries, 2007-2010 (Box 1:, Folder 35)
  - Senate Hearings Testimony, 2008 June (Box 1:, Folder 36)
  - Statement to the UN Security Council, 2008 (Box 1:, Folder 37)
  - Speeches, 2006 (Box 2:, Folder 38)
  - Speeches, 2007 (Box 2:, Folder 39)
  - Speeches, 2008 (Box 2:, Folder 40)
  - Speeches, 2008 (Box 2:, Folder 41)
  - Speeches, 2009 (Box 2:, Folder 42)
  - Speeches, 2010-2011 (Box 2:, Folder 43)
  - Writings, 2006 (Box 2:, Folder 44)
  - Writings, 2007 (Box 2:, Folder 45)
  - Writings by Ronan Farrow, 2006-2008 (Box 2:, Folder 46)
  - Writings by Mia Farrow and Eric Reeves, 2008 (Box 2:, Folder 47)
  - Writings, 2008 (Box 2:, Folder 48)
  - Writings, 2009 (Box 2:, Folder 49)
  - Writings, 2010-2011 (Box 2:, Folder 50)
  - Writings, undated (Box 2:, Folder 51)
  - Travel Notebooks, 2007-2009 (Box 3)
  - Speeches and Writings by others - Gen. Mohamdo, 2008; Several ink jet pages and photocopies with English and Arabic text and signatures, 1 handwritten contextual note by Mia. (Box 5, Folder 55)
- Series III: Audiovisual Materials, 2006-2011
  - Digital Photographs on CD, 2006-2011 (Box 4)